Mario Diaz

Rio Rancho (505) 702-6159

https://github.com/MarioDiaz78

Mdiaz20@cnm.edu | Xavi.jr23@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mario-diaz-jr-400817198/

Objective Statement

Dedicated professional with 18 years of experience at US Foods, transitioning into web development and software development. Proficient in problem-solving, effective communication, and task prioritization. Although new to the technical aspects of the field, I am confident that my transferable skills and learning mindset will fuel my success in this new path.

Skills

 JavaScript 	Full Stack Web HTML	Development • CSS	• React	ţ
 Typescript 	 PostgreSQL 	 Express 	• WebS	torm
GitHub	 Docker 	 DevOps 	• Node	.js
Git	 UX/UI 	• ERD	• Boots	trap 5.2
PythonMATLABCollaboration	JavaLeadershCritical T	•	CommunicatioTime ManagerLearning Mind	ment

Education

In progress (August 2021 – August 2023)

Central New Mexico, Albuquerque

- Major: Associates of Science in Computer Science.
- Degree will be completed in August 2023.

August 1997

University of New Mexico, Albuquerque

- Major: Bachelor of Science in Chemistry.
- Minor: Computer Science in Programming.
- Accumulated 115 credit hours.

Completed (August 2021 – December 2022)

Central New Mexico, Albuquerque

Major: Associates of Science in Health Well/Public Safety Cert,
 Integrated Studies Degree

Experience

April 2021 - March 2023

US Foods, Albuquerque- Day Warehouse Forklift Operator-Lead

- Led pre-shift meetings to address safety concerns from the previous day.
- Adjusted task assignments based on daily case counts to optimize workload.
- Analyzed productivity barriers from previous days and devised operational enhancements.
- Actively involved in various operations from receiving to managing divers.
- Demonstrated commitment to team's success through a hands-on approach.
- Prioritized transparency and optimization of individual skills.
- Made significant contributions to collective team success and efficiency.
- Managed the inbound scheduling to ensure timely and efficient operations.
- Supervised Capstone lumpers, an external service, ensuring they correctly broke down trailer loads to our warehouse standards.

- Ensured Capstone used unbroken pallets for product transfer and separation of damaged goods for return to the trailers.
- Maintained quality control by addressing mistakes directly and instructing Capstone on corrections.
- Oversaw Capstone's performance, ensuring their service met our operational expectations.
- Liaised with the Capstone manager to address and resolve any issues.

May 2019 – April 2021

US Foods, Albuquerque- Shipping/Receiving Clerk-Lead

- Prepared inbound documents and allocated receiving doors for incoming drivers.
- Processed all purchase orders and ensured clearance by the end of each day.
- Managed the discrepancy report to address any mismatches or issues.
- Scheduled all backhauls, collaborating with the buying department; compiled weekly backhaul reports.
- Handled out-of-stock and damage claims to address any inventory issues.
- Conducted pre-shift meetings to facilitate team communication and workflow planning.

January 2019 - April 2019

US Foods, Albuquerque - Receiver

- Verified inbound product identification against invoices and receiving paperwork to ensure correct pack/size, quantity, product quality, and temperature, as well as pallet ti/hi.
- Checked temperatures of all inbound frozen and refrigerated products to meet food safety standards and RRE requirements, adhering to HACCP guidelines.
- Confirmed the quantity of each product, making sure the count aligns with the documentation.
 Reported any discrepancies for accurate inventory level adjustments in the system.

January 2016 - December 2018

US foods, Albuquerque - Day Warehouse Forklift

- Letdowns in each department; Cooler, Dry, and Freezer.
- Put-aways in each department, Cooler, Dry, and Freezer.
- Selected Will calls.
- PIR put-aways.
- Assisted with driver check-in for about a month, as per Joshua Robertson, the previous VP of Operations, before a permanent hire was made for the position.
- Supported other US Foods locations nationally with selection and forklifting operations, including sites in Topeka, Norcross, St. Louis, and Columbia, as part of the ICPM initiative.

January 2015 - December 2015

US Foods, Albuquerque- Night Warehouse Selector

- Selection in all areas: Freezer, Cooler, and Dry.
- Forklift in all areas: Freezer, Cooler, and Dry.
- Load trailers.
- Trained employees in loading, selection, and forklift operation.

July 2012 - December 2014

US Foods, Albuquerque- Night Warehouse Forklift-Lead

- Managed various tasks throughout the night including clerical work, loading, selecting, and operating a forklift.
- Conducted driver check-in procedures for routes from El Paso and Las Cruces.
- Stepped in to either open or close the shift during instances when the supervisor or manager had the day(s) off.
- Regularly opened and closed the Friday shift.
- Trained employees in loading, selection, and forklift operation.

March 2004 - June 2012

US Foods, Albuquerque- Night Warehouse Selector

- Selection in all areas: Freezer, Cooler, and Dry.
- Forklift in all areas: Freezer, Cooler, and Dry.
- Loaded trailers.
- Trained employees in loading, selection, and forklift operation.

References available upon request.